Guide to the Collection of musical autographs,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Cataloged Documents and Manuscripts
  - Seidl, Anton Autobiographical notes: "Im Jahr, 1872", [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages a.m.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    [With exhibition note (translated excerpt): Seidl's description of his early career. "There is only one artist among conductors and that is Hans Richter."]
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "A Musician's Retort" from The North American Review., [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 pages p.ms.bd., 2 pages photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    [Published response to book on Wagner by Max Nordau. Pages 740-743. ]
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "Musikalische Plauderei", [n.p.], [n.d.], (12 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Seidl, Anton Note-book of stage directions for the first performances of "der Ring des Nibelungen.", Bayreuth, 1876, (27 pages xerox copy (for reader use)) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Seidl, Anton Notebook containing stage directions for the first performance of "Der Ring des Nibelungen.", Bayreuth, 1876, (1 book a.ms.s., 1 page photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    [Readers must use xerox copy of this item. With exhbition notes. ]
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "Das Rheingold", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Seidl, Anton "In Wahnfried", Bayreuth, 1878, (1 page a.ms., 2 copies t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    [From Seidl's diary.]
  - Seidl, Anton "Tagebuch Wagner Theater", [n.p.], 1882, (4 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Seidl, Anton "Tristan and Isolde" in Wein: Correspondenz aus Wien in der Suddeutschen Presse", Vienna, September 1883, (5 pages a.ms. (hand unknown)) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "Ueber das Dirigiren", [n.p.], [n.d.], (18 pages p.ms. 2 copies) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    [Essay on conducting published in "Bayreuther Blatter." Pages 3-18]
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "Wagner in America", [n.p.], [n.d.], (5 pages a.ms., 1 page notes photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    [With exhibition notes.]
  - Seidl, Anton Essay, "Wagner's Influence on Present-day Composers", [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 pages p.ms., 6 pages photocopies) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    [Pages 47-49 from unidentified publication. ]
  - Seidl, Anton "Wie Wagner selbst uber Seidl dachte, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    [Seidl's manuscript of an article on his relations with Wagner. On stationery: Everett House, Union Square, New York.]
  - Wagner, Richard 1813-1883 Published by Mainz, B. Schott's Sohner. "Die Meistersinger von Nurnberg" inscribed to Seidl and signed by Wagner in 1872, [n.p.], 1856, (41 pages bd.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    [Gift of Ruth Schleichen 21 June 1999. Exhibition note "Full orchestra score of Act I, scene i and ii. A note in Anton Seidl's hand indicates that the manuscript is in Wagner's hand."]
  - Wagner, Richard Published by Mainz. Printed book, "Siegfried", 1876, (98 pages bd.) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    [With notes by Anton Seidl.]
  - Wagner, Richard. Full score, Scenes One and Two, "Die Walkure.", n.p., 1856, (24 pages xerox copies of manuscript) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    [Note by Anton Seidl indicates that this is probably in Wagner's own hand. Reader must use copy of original.]
  - Wolff, Hermann Seidl's contract with Hermann Wolff for the performing rights for Wagner's Symphony in C major., [n.p.], 1887-1888, (2 pages a.d.s., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    [With postmarked envelope and exhibition note.]
  - Wagner, Richard Full score, Scenes One and Two, "Die Walkure", [n.p.], ca. 1856, (24 pages a.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    [Original not to be used by readers. Note by Anton Seidl indictaes that this is probably in Wagner's own hand.]
  - Auguste Seidl-Kraus Library of Congress Certificate of donation; copyright notices., New York, NY, 4 June 1900, (1 page a. and t.ms.s., 3 pages a. and t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Trustees of Columbia College Trustees meeting minutes detailing participation in memorial service at the Metropolitan opera house for Anton Seidl., New York City., 1 May 1899, (2 pages p.l.s.) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Photograph of concert performance conducted by Anton Seidl., [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 11x14 inches) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Portrait of Anton Seidl, "1850-1898", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 engraving 12 x 14.5 inches) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - D. Appleton & Co. Portrait of Anton Seidl; engraving from lithograph, [n.p.], 1895, (1 11.25 x 13.5 inches) (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Series III: Clippings and Ephemera
  - Druck von J.B. Hirschfeld Publishers Libretto, "Prolog: Zur Eroffnung des Neuen Gewandhauses", Leipzig, 11 December 1884, (4 pages bd) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Wagner, Richard B. Schott's Soehne (publisher) Facsimile of libretto to "Dit Meistersinger von Nurnberg", Mainz, n.d., (84 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    [Inscription RW on facsimile. Inscription from Seidl to Auguste Seidl questionable.]
  - Seidl, Anton Program Metropolitan Opera directed by Seidl, New York, 12 March 1896, (10 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    [Printed by Dempsey & Carroll, NY.]
  - Program: National Symphony Orchestra, Inc. at Carnegie Hall conducted by Willem Mengelberg, New York, 20 and 22 January 1921, (8 pages ) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    [Program and notes include references to Wagner. ]
  - Wagner, Richard Incomplete printed material: printed photo and pages 278, 289, 310, [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    [Possibly a periodical clipping.]
  - Bayreuther Blatter Periodical featuring articles on Seidl, Bayreuth, 1898, (63 pages bd.s., 63 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    [One copy contains annotations by Auguste Seidl on page 149.]
  - Bayreuther Blatter Periodical with material relating to Seidl, Bayreuth, 1899, (99 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Clippings and ephemera include: 1) Program: Philharmonic Society of New York, 22 April 1892. 2) Printed Seidl obituary (no source). 3) Small envelope marked "Genuine signatures of Anton Seidl" containing 12 signed snippets of paper. 4) Museum pamphlet: "Das Reuter- und Wagner- Museum." 8 pages. 5) Column detailing dedication service for Seidl's urn. 13 January 1906, 1 page with photocopy., v.p., n.d.; 1892 and 1906, (5 items) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Programs. 1) Anton Seidl Subscription Concerts, The Astoria, 1897-1898. 2) Maine Benefit Concert, Waldorf-Astoria, 4 March 1898. 3) The Steinway Hall Programme, Anton Seidl's Second Symphony Soiree, 29 January 1887., New York, 1887-1898, (4 pages bd., 3 pages bd., 10 pages bd.) (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Program: Richard Wagner's "Schriften und Dichtungen" (Tristan and Isolde), Leipzig, 1873, (18 pages bd.s.) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    [Inscribed by Seidl: "Anton Seidl, Bayreuth Dec. 872 (publication date 1873)]
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. v.p., [n.d.]; 1883-1933, (21 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings., v.p., [n.d.]; 1891-1917, (18 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings., v.p., [n.d.]; 1882-1922, (33 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. Originals on file contain possible notes by Seidl or Auguste Seidl., v.p., [n.d.]; 1885-1898, (26 pages photocopies, 6 items orginal) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. Originals on file contain possible notes by Seidl or Auguste Seidl., v.p., [n.d.]; 1897-1898, (15 pages photocopies, 4 items orginal) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. Originals on file contain possible notes by Seidl or Auguste Seidl., v.p., [n.d.]; 1885-1898, (16 pages photocopies, 6 items orginal) (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. Originals on file contain possible notes by Seidl or Auguste Seidl., v.p., [n.d.]; 1882-1897, (15 pages photocopies, 2 items orginal) (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings. Originals on file contain possible notes by Seidl or Auguste Seidl., v.p., [n.d.]; 1886-1893, (16 pages photocopies, 6 items orginal) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper and periodical clippings, v.p., [n.d.] 1885-1936, (29 pages photocopies, 3 items original) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Clippings and ephemera regarding life of Auguste Seidl-Kraus, v.p., 1877, 1885 and 1939, (9 pages photocopies, 1 page original) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    [Includes concert program 25 August 1877 with Auguste Krauss on roster.]
  - Funeral paraphenalia for Anton Seidl, New York, 31 March 1898; 2 May 1898, (2 pages bd, 2 pages bd., 2 pages t.ms., 1 page printed copy, 1 page printed copy, 6 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    [2 copies of announcement; 2 versions of funeral program, 1 copy Memorial program]
  - Concert notes., NY, PA, MD, Washington., [n.d.], (4 pages photocopies, 4 pages originals) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Postcards and photograph, [v.p.], [n.d.]; 1897, (2 p.c., 1 p.c.s., 5 1/8" x 4" photograph, 5 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Programs, Bayreuth, NY, England, 1890-1897, (9 pages printed programs, 9 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Programs, periodical signed Arthur Claapen, notes, v.p., 1882-1895, (6 pages photocopies, 4 pages printed, 12 pages s., 1 page a.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clippings, [n.p], [n.d.]; 1901-1903, (9 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Bayreuth Festival ephemera: postcard, poster, programs, Seidl notes, Bayreuth, 1897, (1 p.c., 1 poster, 2 pages printed, 4 pages printed bd., 2 pages a.s., 6 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    [Notes (letter?) signed by Anton Seidl.]
  - Newspaper clippings., New York, 11 April 1904; 21-22 April 1930, (8 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Wagner, Richard Newspaper and periodical clippings, programs with printed notes and libretto, [n.p.] Bayreuth, 1882-1883; 1917, (21 pages photocopies, 12 items originals ) (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Wagner, Seigfried Newspaper clippings, [n.p.] London, [n.d.] 1896, (1 page photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Series IV: Photographs
  - von Bulow, Sophie (Countess Gravina) with unidentified man, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 x 8 inches) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    [With name in Auguste Seidl's hand.]
  - von Bulow, Blandine and Daniela Fritz Meycke (photographer), Bonn and Koln, [n.d.], (1 calling card 2 1/2 x 4 inches) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    [With names in Auguste Seidl's hand.]
  - von Bulow, Daniela, Bayreuth, 1878, (1 photograph s. 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - von Bulow, Blandine (Thode) and Professor Thode Hans Brand Photograph, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 3 3/4 x 8 inches) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hof-Manufactur fur Photographie Two artistic versions of conductors' silhouettes including Seidl, Wien?, [n.d.], (1 photograph 7 1/4 x 9 3/4 inches, 1 photograph 7 1/4 x 9 3/4 inches) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Corbett, James J. [n.d.], (1 photograph s. 4 1/4 x 6 inches) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    [Signed by Seidl et. al.]
  - Lehmann, Lilli Letzer To Auguste Seidl, Wein; Grunewold?, [1886]; 1923, (1 photograph 8 3/4 x 6 3/4 inches, 1 photograph s. 8 1/4 x 10 inches, 1 page a.n.s.) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    [Inscribed to Auguste Seidl]
  - Ludgwig II "Konig Ludwig II als Schwanritter.", Munchen, 1891, (1 photograph 4 1/2 x 6 3/4 inches) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Seidl, Auguste and Anton, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 3/4 x 6 1/2 inches, duplicate photograph 4 3/4 x 6 1/2) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Seidl, Anton With Hans Richter, Hermann Zumpe, Demetrius Lallas nebst Runkwitz., 1872, (1 photograph 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 page note photocopy.) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    [Inscribed by Richter. Exhibition note: "Hans Richter, first conductor of Der Ring des Nibelungen and his staff. Seidl at extreme right."]
  - Seidl, Anton Includes Seidl at age 17, New York, Bremen, Pest, [n.d.] 1867, 1884, (1 photograph 2 1/2 x 4 inches, 1 photograph 2 1/2 x 4 inches, 3 1/4 x 5 1/4 inches ) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    [With notes written in Auguste's Seidl's hand.]
  - Seidl, Anton, v.p., [n.d.] 1882-1883, (1 photograph, bust 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 photograph, bust 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 photograph, half 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 photograph, 3 ql 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 photograph, 3 ql 4 1/4 x 6 inches) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Seidl, Anton, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 1/2 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Seidl, Anton with dog Wotan, Brighton Beach, 13 July 1895, (1 photograph, s. 12 x 10 inches) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    [With handwritten note possibly by Auguste Seidl to Else Ehrich]
  - Wagner, Cosima and Eva and Siegfried and Isolde. With Frau Adolf Gross, Daniela von Bulow and Professor Thode. Bayreuth, 1887, (1 photograph 6 1/2 x 4 1/4 inches, 1 page note photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    [Incomplete note on verso in the hand of Cosima Wagner; names in Auguste Seidl's hand. Exhibition note: "The Wahnfried circle, Summer, 1887.)]
  - Wagner, Eva and Isolde, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Wagner, Eva, [n.p.] & Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches, 1 photograph 4 1/4 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Wagner, Eva with Daniela and Professor Thode, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 x 5 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    [With names in Auguste Seidl's hand]
  - Wagner, Eva and Siegfried, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 x 5 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Wagner, Isolde, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 1/2 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Richard Wagner Theater, Baytreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 6 1/2 x 4/14 inches) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    [With note written in Auguste Seidl's hand.]
  - Wagner, Siegfried with servants, Bayreuth, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 x 5 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    [With names written in Auguste Seidl's hand.]
  - Wagner, Siegfried, Munchen, [n.d.], (1 photograph 4 1/2 x 6 1/2 inches) (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Wagner, Richard (villa) Wahnfried Villa, Bayreuth, 1886, (1 photograph 6 1/2 x 4 1/4 inches, 1 page note photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    [With name in Auguste Seidl's hand. Exhibition note: Wahnfried, Wagner's villa at Bayreuth, where Seidl lived as a member of the household, 1874-1878.]
- Series V: Scores
  - Score in parts "La Bayamesa", [n.d.], (26 half pages a.ms., 1 page printed score) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    [Orchestration by Anton Seidl.]
  - Song: "Bid Grief and Pain", [n.d.], (2 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    [Signed by Anton Seidl with Auguste Seidl. ]
  - Boccherini, L. Seidl's manuscript of Menuet, [n.d.], (6 half pages a.ms., 1 page note photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    [Exhibition note: Seidl's manuscript of his arrangement of the Boccherini Minuet for string orchestra.]
  - Converse, C. Score: "A New American National Hymn.", 1896 copyright, (1 page a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    [Score by Anton Seidl.]
  - Egressi, Szozat "Hymne", New York, 9 December 1894, (4 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Gottschalk Score "La Gallina: Cuban Dance", [n.p.], 2 July 1896, (7 pages copy with changes by hand) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    [Orchestration by Seidl.]
  - Grieg, Edvard Score "Norwegian Suite", [n.p.], March 1894, (30 pages s. copy with changes by hand, 1 page note photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    [Orchestration by Seidl. Exhibition note "Seidl's manuscript of his orchestration of Grieg's Norwegian Suite."]
  - Haydn Score "Symphonie L'Ours." Violin I, [n.p.], [n.d.], (14 pages a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Liszt, Franz and Hugo Score "Dream", [n.p.], 25 May 1894, (10 pages a.ms.s. with changes in pencil) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Liszt, Franz Score "Spanish Rhapsody", [n.d.], (48 pages bd., copy with changes in pencil) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Lowe, C. Score "Hochzeitslied.", [n.p.], Sept 1901, (16 pages a.ms., bd.) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    [Inscribed by Felix Mottl. Handwritten note: "Mottl was conductor at ? from 1881-1903. At a guess, Mottl conducted this at some concert given in NY in 1903-04 and presented the autograph to Mrs. Seidl." ]
  - Loewe, C. Score "Balladen" in two parts, [n.d.], (50 pages a.ms.s., bd.) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Loewe, C. Score "La Balladen, Parts.", [n.d.], (60 pages a.ms.s., bd., 1 page photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    [Orchestration by Seidl. Cover filed separately for restoration purposes.]
  - Loewe, C. Cover "Balladen.", [n.d.], (2 pages bd., with handwritten notes.) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Mancinelli, L. Score "Scene Veneziane", New York, 25 Jan 1894, (244 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    [Inscribed by Mancinelli to Seidl.]
  - Mascagni, P. Score "Intermezzo Romantico from L'Amico Fritz.", [n.d.], (12 pages a.ms., 1 page photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Mascagni, P. Cover of score "Intermezzo Romantico from L'Amico Fritz.", [n.d.], (2 pages a.ms., bd.) (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Mascagni, Pietro Score "Cavalleria Rusticana", [n.d.], (6 pages a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Monasterio, J. de Score "Adios a la Alhambra!", May 1888, (12 pages bd., 2 pages photocopies) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    [Inscribed by Louisa Terzi on page numbered 55. Original cover moved for restoration purposes.]
  - Monasterio, J. de Published cover for "Adios a la Alhambra!", May 1888, (2 pages ) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    [INEEDS PHOTOCOPY]
  - Riedel Score, Lied aus dem 'T rompeter von Sakkingen.", August 1887, (8 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Schubert Score, Momens Musicals aus Op. 94., [n.d.], (12 pages a.ms. with changes in hand.) (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Score "Bachiana.", [n.d.], (4 pages a.ms.s.) (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Score "Good Night, for Children's Chorus with Pianoforte Accompianment.", 1895, (8 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages p.ms.s. with changes by hand.) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    [Words by Edna Dean Proctor.]
  - Wagner, Richard Score "March"; notes, [n.d.], (18 pages a.ms., 3 pages originals, 3 pages copies) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    [Note in Auguste Seidl's hand questions the attribution of these pages to Wagner.]
  - Wagner, Richard Score "Siegfried im Walde.", 1901, (52 pages a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 26)
    [Signature of copyist Arthur Farwell. Orchestration by Anton Seidl.]
  - Wagner, Richard Score "Trauersinfonie zur Eurinnerung - Weber"; notes., Dresden, 1894, (16 pages a.ms.s., 4 pages original notes, 4 pages copies, 1 hard cover) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    [Signed by Anton Seidl. Exhibition note "Wagner, Trauermusik. Composed for the re-internment of the ashes of Carl Maria von Weber. Dresden, 1944. Scored by Seidl from Wagner's sketches."]
  - Wagner, Richard Early draft, score "Trauersinfonie zur Eurinnerung - Weber", [n.d.], (10 pages a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    [Early draft.]
  - Wagner, Richard. Score "Love Song (Liebesnacht) from Tristan and Isolde.", [n.d.], (18 pages a.ms. ) (Box 6, Folder 29)
    [With changes. Orchestration by Seidl.]
  - Weber, C.M. Score "Die drei Pintos" entr'act. Instr. v. Mahler., [n.d.], (16 pages a.ms.) (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Weber, C.M. 31 Score "Sylvana: Ballet und Chor", [n.d.], (4 pages a.ms.) (Box 6)
  - Maien-Festspiel Score with title page; copied handwritten text with Seidl memorandum; privately printed text; program; score; and notes., Bayreuth, 1878, (4 pages a.ms.s., 23 pages p.ms., 15 pages p.ms., 20 pages, 8 pages a.ms.s., 6 pages ) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    [ORIGINALS NOT FOR READER USE. Contains one posted envelope. Exhibition note "Maien-Festspiel: Dramatic poem honoring Wagner, prepared by the household as an elaborate surprise for his 65th birthday, May 22, 1878. Acted by the Wagner children. Music arranged from Wagner's operas and conducted by Seidl." ]
  - Maein-Festspiel. Photocopies of originals for reader use., Bayreuth, 1878, (51 pages photocopies) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    [Photocopies of previous file.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Choral Fantasie: Director's Score, Tams-Witmark Music Library, Inc.: New York, 1781, (56 pages bd.) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    [With Seidl's notes written in pencil.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Choral Fantasy (1781), A.M. Tams Music Library, Inc.: New York, [n.d.], (25 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    [With handwritten notes.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Choral Fantasie," Op. 80. Parts for vocals., Jordens and Martens: New York, [n.d.], (8 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Orchestration: Choral Fantasy 1781, Op. 80. (Parts), A.W. Tams Music Library, Inc.: New York, [n.d.], (39 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Chor-Fantasie," Op. 80. Parts, Breitkopf & Hartels Orchesterbibliothek: Weisbaden Germany, [n.d.], (3 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    [With notes in pencil.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Orchestration of Leid No. 1. Parts., A.W. Tams Music Library, Inc.: New York, [n.d.], (43 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    [Some with notes.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Die Ruinen von Athen," Op. 114. Director's score., Breitkopf and Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (24 pages bd.) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Die Ruinen von Athen," Op. 114. Parts (44)., Breitkopf and Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (71 pages, 18 pages bd.) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Leonore Overture No. 3. Parts (Violin I)., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (8 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Leonore Overture No. 3. Parts (Violin II)., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (7 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    [Some with handwritten notes.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Leonore Overture No. 3. Parts (Viola)., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (4 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Leonore Overture No. 3. Parts (Cello and Bass)., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (7 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Leonore Overture No. 3. Parts (Winds and Brass)., Breitkopf & Hartel: Leipzig, [n.d.], (21 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - J.S. Bach P77.6. Conductor's score and 31 parts., [n.d.], (12 pages bd., 31 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - J.S. Bach P66. 9 "Siciliano." Conductor's score and parts., August Wilhelmj: Berlin, [n.d.], (8 pages bd., 15 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - J.S. Bach Violin Sonata No. 6 in E Major: Prelude and Gavotte en Rondo. Conductor's score and parts., [n.d.], (2 folios bd., 76 pages) (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - J.S. Bach "Passascaglia." Parts., [n.d.], (156 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - J.S. Bach Brandenburg Concerto No. 6 (B major). Score., Breitkopf & Hartel: Germany, [n.d.], (26 pages bd., s.) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    [Printed cover indicates "Nr. 9." Signed by Egon Ebert.]
  - Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel "Ein Marchen: Fantasie," op. 40. Parts with piano accompainment., [n.d.], (84 pages bd.) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    [Title page written by hand. ]
  - Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel "Honeymoon: Valse Lente." Parts., 1894 copyright, (31 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 20)
    [Unsigned inscription to Anton Seidl on first page, Violin I.]
  - Bach, Carl Philipp Emanuel "Fantasy: Nachriefan Weber." Parts and "Director Stimme", New York, [n.d.], (86 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    [Notes and extra pages in pencil.]
  - Bach, Johann Christian P61. Symphony in B flat. Parts., New York, [n.d.], (21 folios bd.) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    [Changes, notes, and new parts in pencil.]
  - Bach, W.F. P87.6 "Heilig, Heilig ist Gott." Score and parts for chorus and instruments., [n.d.], (7 folios a.ms.bd. fair copy) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    [Arranged by Arnold Schering. "Unfinished manuscript."]
  - Bach, E. "Das Abendglocklein." Parts., New York, [n.d.], (24 pages, 6 pages a.ms. fair copy) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    [Handwritten parts in copyist's hand.]
  - Auzende, A.M. "Entr-acte pour Le Roman Comique." Score and parts., Paris, 1889, (1 folio bd., 41 pages ) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Prometheus Overture," Op. 43. Parts. [n.d.], (38 folios, 1 folio a.ms. fair copy) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    [With notes. Handwritten parts in copyist's hand.]
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von "Romance, Violin and Orchestra." No. 2, Op. 80. [n.d.], (11 folios, 20 folios a.ms. fair copy) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig von Namenseier Overture. Parts., [n.d.], (32 folios, 4 folios a.ms. fair copy) (Box 8, Folder 28)